<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><tv date="20230213">
<channel id="Frikanalen.no"><display-name>Frikanalen</display-name><icon src="https://i.imgur.com/rY3Owxl.png"/><url>https://frikanalen.no</url></channel>
<programme start="20230213000200 +0000" stop="20230213001413 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Keith Chen: Could your language affect your ability to save money?</title><desc lang="no">What can economists learn from linguists? Behavioral economist Keith Chen introduces a fascinating pattern from his research: that languages without a concept for the future -- &quot;It rain tomorrow,&quot; instead of &quot;It will rain tomorrow&quot; -- correlate strongly with high savings rates. &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.ted.com/2013/02/19/saving-for-a-rainy-day-keith-chen-on-language-that-forecasts-weather-and-behavior/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Read more about Chen’s explorations »&lt;/a&gt; TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213001500 +0000" stop="20230213005217 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">ifupdown2, the ultimate Network Interface Manager : progress and status - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">Existing tools for network interface configuration have several shortcomings when applied to network switches. These include the lack of ability to handle interface dependencies, incremental updates to interface configuration without disruption, and interface configuration validation. The lack of such functionality increases operational burden. We introduced ifupdown2, a new network interface manager for Linux. ifupdown2 solves these problems through an implementation based on dependency graphs. The purpose of this talk is to briefly describes network interface configuration on Linux, the problems that arise when configuring a network switch and how ifupdown2 solves these problems and increases operational efficiencies overall. This talk mostly targets networking people. We also want to encourage people to contribute to this project by writing their own addon module to support new protocols (e.g. B.A.T.M.A.N.) : https://github.com/CumulusNetworks/ifupdown2 https://packages.debian.org/sid/ifupdown2 Via this talk we also want to give a general up-date on the project. What we added over the year (e.g. VRF, etc.) and what is coming (e.g. better netlink support, better performance..etc.) Talk (45 mins) session with Julien Fortin during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213005300 +0000" stop="20230213015705 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Trust, Elections and Twitter - Patricia Aas</title><desc lang="no">What happened from beginning to end. What made the news and what didn&apos;t. How did it feel to be in it and how I was treated by the public, by the government and by the media. How transparency and suspiciousness is fundamental to an election system and how the lack of transparency drove me to dig further into the ballot counting system in Norway.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213015800 +0000" stop="20230213015835 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Infoplakat Frikanalen</title><desc lang="no">Informasjon om Frikanalen</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213015900 +0000" stop="20230213024323 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Virtual Machines and Where to Find Them</title><desc lang="no">Viua VM is a greenfield virtual machine designed for parallel execution. Its instruction set aims to facilitate writing reliable, correct, concurrent software. Such an undertaking is not completed in a day or two - work on Viua started in December 2014, and is still ongoing. Viua positions itself as a contender to the throne currently occupied by Erlang&apos;s VM - BEAM. Apart from a technical overview, this talk will give a tour of the &quot;softer&quot; problems one may encounter while working on a piece of non-trivial Free Software. It will also discuss how work on such software may affect one&apos;s position in the academia and in the business world. This will be described from an undergraduate student&apos;s point of view, early in their carreer.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213024400 +0000" stop="20230213025342 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Kirby Ferguson: Embrace the remix</title><desc lang="no">Nothing is original, says Kirby Ferguson, creator of Everything is a Remix. From Bob Dylan to Steve Jobs, he says our most celebrated creators borrow, steal and transform. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213025400 +0000" stop="20230213035309 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Hva prosjektledere bør vite om softwareutviklere</title><desc lang="no">Softwareutviklingsprosjekter har en tendens til å gå over tid og budsjett. Dette er det mange grunner til. Foredraget vil legge hovedvekt på en gjennomgåelse av den psykologiske faglitteraturen på området gjennom de siste femten år. Den kan deles i to: Den som er utført av ingeniører, og den som er utført av psykologer. Ingeniørene ser på det vi er interessert i, altså hvilke variabler som fører til produktivitet, men de har en tendens til å gjøre veldig pussige metodevalg, slik at resultatene blir vanskelige å integrere med eksisterende kunnskap. Psykologene pleier å holde seg til ortodoks og nyttig metodevalg, men pleier å studere veldig perifere ting, som hva som skal til for at programmerere skal bli glade i hverandre. Rolf Lindgren er psykolog fra UiO. Han har utviklet SMS-applikasjoner i Java og MySQL, og skrev koden som konverterte UiOs studiehåndbøker fra studiekonsulentenes XML-dokumenter til pdf for utskrift. Han deltok i, og ledet avslutningen av, et treårig forskningsprosjekt ved Det Norske Veritas som hadde som formål å identifisere menneskelige risikofaktorer i softwareutviklingsprosjekter. Han er seniorrådgiver i Dignus rekruttering og rådgivning. NUUG talk from 2007-10-09.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213035400 +0000" stop="20230213043425 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Citizenfour - Samtale med Snowden-advokat Patrick Toomey og Jon Wessel-Aas før visning</title><desc lang="no">Samtale med Patrick Toomey, en av advokatene til Edward Snowden, og Jon Wessel-Aas før forpremieren av Citizenfour 2015-04-15. Arrangert i samarbeid med Fritt Ord, Tour de Force og Ny Tid.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213043500 +0000" stop="20230213053257 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Lightning Talks 2</title><desc lang="no">Lightning talks from Day 2 of FSCONS 2017. Recorded by NUUG for FSCONS.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213053300 +0000" stop="20230213054702 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - David Pizarro: The strange politics of disgust</title><desc lang="no">What does a disgusting image have to do with how you vote? Equipped with surveys and experiments, psychologist David Pizarro demonstrates a correlation between sensitivity to disgusting cues -- a photo of feces, an unpleasant odor -- and moral and political conservatism. (Filmed at TEDxEast.) TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213054800 +0000" stop="20230213061019 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FLOSSing for healthier society - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">Code For South Africa use technology to promote informed decision making for social change. This talk points out some of the tech and principles we use to maximise our positive impact on society. From building a data gathering platform for citizen journalists, to releasing government financial data, FLOSS and a lean process helps deliver the best bang for the buck in these important partnerships. Often avoiding writing new software delivers more value, and frees us so that when we do need to write something, it counts. Open Weekend session with J.D. Bothma during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213061100 +0000" stop="20230213063258 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TAK - Fred i Palestina krever oppgjør med sionist-jødisk tenkning</title><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213063300 +0000" stop="20230213074122 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Enkel grafisk nettverksplanlegging med PrimeDesktop</title><desc lang="no">Dette foredraget handler om PrimeDesktop - et kartleggingsverktøy spesielt rettet mot nettverksadministratorer, som skal hjelpe med driften av og rundt et nettverk. Verktøyet kan hjelpe med å holde oversikt over blant annet topologi, nettverks regler og brukergruppers rettigheter, samt hardware og software i nettverket. Målet med prosjektet er å gjøre drift av nettverk mer håndterlig, oversiktlig og kostnadseffektivt ved å hjelpe med opplæring, feilsøking og vedlikehold på et vis der selv nybegynnere kan komme igang med jobben. Bahram gir en kort introduksjon til prosjektet, forteller litt om hvordan verktøyet kan være nyttig i forskjellige nettverk sammenheng og gir en demonstrasjon for å vise forskjellige egenskaper ved verktøyet. Bahram Malaekeh er prosjektleder og utvikler i PrimeDesktop, og har funnet motivasjonen for prosjektet etter erfaringer han gjorde som nettverksadministrator hos Elkjøp. Bahram har studert ved Dataingeniør-linjen ved Høyskolen i Oslo hvor han oppdaget han ikke kunne bestemme seg om det var Mark Burgess eller Richard Stallman som var hans idol. NUUG-foredrag fra 2010-11-09.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213074200 +0000" stop="20230213075918 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Developing plugins for FreeRTC - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">WebRTC, also known as RTCWeb, puts two-way media streaming capabilities into the web browser and provides an API to manage them (starting and stopping calls) from the JavaScript embedded in any web page. The technology has been pioneered in the two major browsers, Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome. Other browsers have been following their lead. There was some instability in the early years of WebRTC but since mid-2014 the technology has stabilised significantly. There have been some pseudo-WebRTC solutions as well, specifically, browser plugins that offer behavior similar to WebRTC with an emphasis on a specific provider. These solutions are not true WebRTC and they are largely becoming irrelevant now that most users have upgraded to browsers with genuine WebRTC support built in. WebRTC provides a mechanism for peer-to-peer media streaming (audio or video) but it does not specify the use of any particular signalling system, the mechanism responsible for locating other users and routing calls to them. The talk is going to include how to develop FreeRTC plugins for third party applications. Code snippets will be shared. Now it is possible to talk to each other from different cms systems. Talk (20 mins) session with Mesut Can Gurle during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213080000 +0000" stop="20230213085058 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Om beslaget i popcorn-time.no saken</title><desc lang="no">Økokrim beslagla i vår domenet popcorn-time.no. I den forbindelse gjennomførte de beslag også hos IMC AS og deres regnskapsfører. Morten Eriksen, daglig leder i IMC AS, gir her gi sin versjon av hvordan dette opplevdes fra hans side. NUUG talk from 2016-11-08.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213085100 +0000" stop="20230213090633 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Chris Urmson: How a driverless car sees the road</title><desc lang="no">Statistically, the least reliable part of the car is ... the driver. Chris Urmson heads up Google&apos;s driverless car program, one of several efforts to remove humans from the driver&apos;s seat. He talks about where his program is right now, and shares fascinating footage that shows how the car sees the road and makes autonomous decisions about what to do next. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213090700 +0000" stop="20230213100300 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Teckids: The Free Software Youth Organisation</title><desc lang="no">Teckids is a youth organisation from Germany, aiming at establishing a free software community among children and adolescents (basically pupils). Regularly running youth programmes at FOSS conferences where children take part in workshops about many aspects of technology and computer science, Teckids provides the necessary entry level to the free software community. Being a community organisation for young people, Teckids entirely relies on engaging those young people in all aspects of the organisation, starting from tutoring in workshops up to participating as board members. This concept brings a whole bunch of quite complicated and hard processes with it, but is entirely worth while. We would like to introduce our work to interested participants in Norway, to present the idea behind the organisation, and maybe find people who would like to engage in the project in Norway. Eike and Nik are two members of Teckids e.V. in Germany. Nik is chairperson and founding member of the organisation, and Eike, now 16 years old, is the tutor who got everything rolling back when he was 11 years old and held his first PyGame workshops at FrOSCon. The two are now lead developers of the Veripeditus project, a new tool to get young people interested in gaming involved in programming using free software tools. NUUG talk from 2017-08-08.</desc><category lang="no">Barn og ungdom</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213100400 +0000" stop="20230213104549 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">EuroBSDCon 2019, Lillehammer: Wireless Fidelity with bwfm(4) - Patrick Wildt</title><desc lang="no">The Broadcom Wireless FullMAC chip has been one of the biggest hurdles in properly supporting Apple MacBooks in the recent years. But that has not been the only place where this chip has popped up. bwfm(4) is a new OpenBSD driver that supports these chips and was also ported to NetBSD. This talks gives an overview of the chip, an in-depth view into how one communicates with the chip on the three different supported busses, and the higher layer protocol that’s being run on top. It also shows issues properly combining the driver with the OpenBSD net80211 stack, which isn’t written to handle FullMACs. The talk also shows the Firmware and NVRAM distribution issues.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213104600 +0000" stop="20230213105812 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Rajiv Maheswaran: The math behind basketball&apos;s wildest moves</title><desc lang="no">Basketball is a fast-moving game of improvisation, contact and, ahem, spatio-temporal pattern recognition. Rajiv Maheswaran and his colleagues are analyzing the movements behind the key plays of the game, to help coaches and players combine intuition with new data. Bonus: What they&apos;re learning could help us understand how humans move everywhere. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Idrett</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213105900 +0000" stop="20230213111743 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond Alis kvarter IV</title><desc lang="no">Trond Ali snakker med Dr. Salim om tostatsløsningen</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213111800 +0000" stop="20230213122738 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">OpenID introduksjon</title><desc lang="no">Dette foredraget presenterer hva OpenID er og hva den kan gjøre for deg. Vi vil demonstrere OpenID i en demo hvro vi bruker maskinvare-basert autentisering fra Yubico for forbedret sikkerhet. OpenId er en åpen arkitektur for web-basert brukerautentisering. En av dens fordeler er at den lar deg som web-utvikler unngå maset ved å vedlikeholde en egen bruker/passord-database, med de sikkerhetsproblemene dette innebærer. Fordelen for deg som bruker av systemet er at du kan redusere antall brukernavn/passord-kombinasjoner du må forholde deg til. Presentasjonen fokuserer på egenskaper i forhold til brukervennlighet og berører kun overfladisk de underliggende kryptografiske mekansimer. Simon Josefsson arbeider som uavhengig konsulent med fri sikkerhets-programvare. Han vedlikeholder GNU implementasjonen av TLS, Kerberos og SASL protekollene. Han deltar i IETF for å standardisere fremtidige versjoner.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213122800 +0000" stop="20230213123405 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Marco Tempest: The electric rise and fall of Nikola Tesla</title><desc lang="no">Combining projection mapping and a pop-up book, Marco Tempest tells the visually arresting story of Nikola Tesla -- called “the greatest geek who ever lived” -- from his triumphant invention of alternating current to his penniless last days. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213123500 +0000" stop="20230213132544 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">ForgeRock</title><desc lang="no">Månedens tema er: «ForgeRock - Et norsk selskap med global satsing basert på fri programvare» med Stein Myrseth. Foredraget vil foregå på norsk: Foredraget vil kort gå igjennom forretningsmodellen til ForgeRock siden den er basert på videreføring av flere fri programvarebaserte produkter som Oracle ikke var interessert i når de overtok Sun. De utvikler i tillegg også sine egne produkter. Uten en fri programvaremodell for disse produktene ville ikke ForgeRock vært en realitet. Foredagsholderen vil beskrive hvordan tjener de penger på fri programvare. Presentasjonen vil også dekke generelle problemstillinger med Identity &amp; Access Management rundt områder som autentisering, autorisasjon, føderering og provisioning. Tidligere OpenSSO, nå OpenAM som de viderefører vil bli kort beskrevet sammen med resten av deres I3-platformstrategi. Stein Myrseth er Head of product Management hos ForgeRock. Hans rolle er å definere de videre strategiske retningslinjer for deres I3-strategi, samt</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213132600 +0000" stop="20230213133903 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond Alis Kvarter - Israel og Sionisme</title><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213134000 +0000" stop="20230213140310 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">What I learned from 365 days of contributing to Open Source projects - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">Last year, I committed myself to contribute to Open Source projects, daily, for 365 days in a row. The talk will tell a story of this experience, the difficulties encountered, lessons learned and why (or not) you should consider doing this as well. No technical background is required. Talk (20 mins) session with Dieter Adriaenssens during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213140400 +0000" stop="20230213140716 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">En sang i uka</title><desc lang="no">I dagens torsdagsinnslag møter vi Andreas Gregersen som har satt seg et stort mål for året: han skal nemlig lage en sang hver eneste uke i 2020. Vi besøkte ham i det han skulle lage sang for uke 4. Tittelen på sangen ble Empo Tv.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213140800 +0000" stop="20230213142051 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">M@thias&apos; verden del 3</title><category lang="no">Barn og ungdom</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213142100 +0000" stop="20230213144430 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Debian/Linux in Developing Nations - Challenges and Rewards - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">FOSS software is undoubtedly the best option for developing nations, where financial resources may limit access to proprietary software. At the same time, using Debian/Linux also has its share of challenges in these settings, as there may be infrastructure issues to contend with. This talk shares the joys I have personally experienced while using Debian in Swaziland, as well as the challenges that I have faced, and also seen others face too. Perhaps the audience may be able to suggest ways to overcome some of the issues involved, and thus get more exposure and adoption for Debian in developing countries. Talk (20 mins) session with Sicelo Mhlongo during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213144500 +0000" stop="20230213150257 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Sir Ken Robinson: Bring on the learning revolution!</title><desc lang="no">In this poignant, funny follow-up to his fabled 2006 talk, Sir Ken Robinson makes the case for a radical shift from standardized schools to personalized learning -- creating conditions where kids&apos; natural talents can flourish. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213150300 +0000" stop="20230213152003 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Maryn McKenna: What do we do when antibiotics don’t work any more?</title><desc lang="no">Penicillin changed everything. Infections that had previously killed were suddenly quickly curable. Yet as Maryn McKenna shares in this sobering talk, we&apos;ve squandered the advantages afforded us by that and later antibiotics. Drug-resistant bacteria mean we&apos;re entering a post-antibiotic world — and it won&apos;t be pretty. There are, however, things we can do ... if we start right now. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Beredskap</category><category lang="no">Samfunn</category><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category><category lang="no">Velferd</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213152100 +0000" stop="20230213152629 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond Alis kvarter V</title><desc lang="no">Malak forteller</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213152700 +0000" stop="20230213152843 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Annerledes av Margrete</title><desc lang="no">Margrete (33) har skrevet og framført et dikt om å leve med en funksjonshemming. Selv har hun asperger-syndrom.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213152900 +0000" stop="20230213152948 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Frikanalen Informasjonsfilm</title><desc lang="no">Info!</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213153000 +0000" stop="20230213162155 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Daily Tech News Show 23. May 2016</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213162200 +0000" stop="20230213165758 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Less passwords, more security: mass administration of MariaDB servers with socket authentication - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">In this talk I&apos;ll explain how socket authentication in MariaDB works and how it makes the life of system administrators easier when they can do all maintenance as root, without the need of additional passwords. Life without extra passwords is also more secure, as there is less to leak or loose. Socket authentication in MariaDB is by default enabled in Debian. Talk (45 mins) session with Otto Kekäläinen during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213165800 +0000" stop="20230213165919 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Kopiering er ikke tyveri</title><category lang="no">Barn og ungdom</category><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213170000 +0000" stop="20230213175814 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Gud, Jehova, Jesus og Den Hellige Ånd</title><desc lang="no">De er forskjellige forteller bibelen</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213175900 +0000" stop="20230213185655 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Keynote: TBA - Linda Sandvik</title><desc lang="no">Linda Sandvik&apos;s keynote at FSCONS 2017 Recorded by NUUG for FSCONS.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213185700 +0000" stop="20230213185930 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Caminandes 3: Llamigos</title><desc lang="no">I denne episoden av tegnefilmserien Caminandes blir vi enda bedre kjent med vår helt Koro. Det er vinter i Patagonia, og det er lite mat. Llamaen Koro møter den plagsomme pingvinen Oti i en episk kamp om siste saftige bær.</desc><category lang="no">Barn og ungdom</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213190000 +0000" stop="20230213190315 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Demo foran Stortinget</title><desc lang="no">Demo foran Stortinget om avtalen mellom Bahrain, Israel, FAE og USA</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213190400 +0000" stop="20230213195017 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Testing Debian-Installer using jenkins.debian.{net,org} - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">... or how to stop worrying and have fun hacking on d-i without needing to be scared about breaking everything The objective here is to let people push to feature branches and find out later how much damage they would have done had they put that into d-i. The hope being that the answer will often be &quot;None&quot; This should encourage people to do more work on d-i. The talk will also serve to demonstrate the use of Cucumber and Jenkins that we have for running the tests. Talk (45 mins) session with Philip Hands during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213195100 +0000" stop="20230213195606 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Marco Tempest: The magic of truth and lies (and iPods)</title><desc lang="no">Using three iPods like magical props, Marco Tempest spins a clever, surprisingly heartfelt meditation on truth and lies, art and emotion. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213195700 +0000" stop="20230213195914 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Torsdagsinnslag 6. februar: Spor3</title><desc lang="no">Etter kommunesammenslåingen av Ski og Oppegård til Nordre Follo kommune, ble Rådhuset og de fleste innbyggertjenestene, som f.eks. servicetorg og NAV-kontor lagt til Ski. Det skaper utfordringer for rullestolbrukere på Kolbotn som ønsker å ta toget til Ski.</desc><category lang="no">Velferd</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213200000 +0000" stop="20230213205229 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Stopp NATO 5. november 2022, del 1</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213205300 +0000" stop="20230213224512 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Politisk debatt om gründerpolitikk i Oslo</title><desc lang="no">Norwegian Unix User Group (NUUG) inviterer deg til debatt med topp-politikere om gründerpolitikk i Oslo 2. september, på Teknologhuset kl. 18-20.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213224600 +0000" stop="20230213225629 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Chris Milk: How virtual reality can create the ultimate empathy machine</title><desc lang="no">Chris Milk uses cutting edge technology to produce astonishing films that delight and enchant. But for Milk, the human story is the driving force behind everything he does. In this short, charming talk, he shows some of his collaborations with musicians including Kanye West and Arcade Fire, and describes his latest, mind-bending experiments with virtual reality. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213225700 +0000" stop="20230213225926 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Caminandes 2: Gran Dillama</title><desc lang="no">Llamaen Koro erfarer at gresset er grønnere på den andre siden av gjerdet, og at veien dit kan være lang.</desc><category lang="no">Barn og ungdom</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213230000 +0000" stop="20230213232219 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FLOSSing for healthier society - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">Code For South Africa use technology to promote informed decision making for social change. This talk points out some of the tech and principles we use to maximise our positive impact on society. From building a data gathering platform for citizen journalists, to releasing government financial data, FLOSS and a lean process helps deliver the best bang for the buck in these important partnerships. Often avoiding writing new software delivers more value, and frees us so that when we do need to write something, it counts. Open Weekend session with J.D. Bothma during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230213232300 +0000" stop="20230214002335 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Konfigurasjonsstyring med Chef</title><desc lang="no">Chef er konfigurasjonsstyring som er lett å komme i gang med, og som er i stand til å vokse med deg. Fokus er ikke kun på enkeltmaskiner, men på hele arkitekturen. Chef har støtte for søk, god separasjon av oppskrifter og data og et veldefinert API som klienter bruker for å interagere med Chef-serveren. Vi vil se på designvalg, egenskaper og gå gjennom et enkelt eksempel på bruk av Chef. Tollef Fog Heen har drevet med fri programvare siden en gang på 1990-tallet og vært Debian-utvikler i over ti år. Han jobber for tiden i Varnish Software som systemadministrator og bidrar til forskjellige fri programvare-prosjekter, herunder Chef.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214002400 +0000" stop="20230214010517 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">The Supreme Court of DFSG-Free? - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">There is no Free Software project in the world with Debian&apos;s commitment to representative governance. Debian has a Constitution, recall and referendum ballot initiatives, and accountable, elected bodies. However, any representative system, no matter how well structured, has its gaps that can be exploited politically. In this talk, I will first confess how I once used such a gap in the licensing approval process as part of package uploads to successfully reach political aims outside of Debian. I will explain how and why I did it, and why it was possible. While at the time, I was glad the system could be slightly &quot;gamed&quot;, in hindsight, I&apos;d like to draw the Debian&apos;s community attention this gap open for political opportunists and discuss changes in the political structure to prevent similar political exploitation in future. Ultimately, Debian ftp-masters fully control, absent a specific General Resolution, interpretation of the DFSG. While, technically speaking, no specific package upload refusal nor approval sets any overarching Debian policy on a particular license, the ftp-masters&apos; decisions do become a de-facto precedence-based system, much like a common-law Court system, since overturning such decisions would typically require a General Resolution in practice. This talk will explore the socio-political ramifications of the current system of licensing decision-making in Debian, pontificate on ways it can be improved (and why it should be), and seek audience participation on whether the analysis presented is accurate and/or if the outcome of that analysis warrants changes in the existing system. Talk (45 mins) session with Bradley Kuhn during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214010600 +0000" stop="20230214010915 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Demo foran Stortinget</title><desc lang="no">Demo foran Stortinget om avtalen mellom Bahrain, Israel, FAE og USA</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214011000 +0000" stop="20230214011143 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Annerledes av Margrete</title><desc lang="no">Margrete (33) har skrevet og framført et dikt om å leve med en funksjonshemming. Selv har hun asperger-syndrom.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214011200 +0000" stop="20230214020909 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Hjelp, jeg skal holde tale!</title><desc lang="no">De fleste av oss kommer før eller siden opp i en situasjon hvor vi er nødt til å snakke til en forsamling, det være seg privat (konfirmasjon, bryllup, runde fødselsdager, generalforsamling i borettslaget o.l.) eller i yrkeslivet (julebord og andre firmafester, seminarer, fagforeningsmøter o.l.). Noen ganger skjer det spontant og uforberedt fordi munnen bobler over med det hjertet er fullt av. Andre ganger ? og de er som regel de vanskelige ? er det (mer eller mindre) nøye planlagt, og forventningene både fra en selv og fra forsamlingen kan virke lammende. Hva kan en skuespiller lære oss om å takle forventningspresset og å forene nøye forberedelse med spontanitet og entusiasme?</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214021000 +0000" stop="20230214030044 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">ForgeRock</title><desc lang="no">Månedens tema er: «ForgeRock - Et norsk selskap med global satsing basert på fri programvare» med Stein Myrseth. Foredraget vil foregå på norsk: Foredraget vil kort gå igjennom forretningsmodellen til ForgeRock siden den er basert på videreføring av flere fri programvarebaserte produkter som Oracle ikke var interessert i når de overtok Sun. De utvikler i tillegg også sine egne produkter. Uten en fri programvaremodell for disse produktene ville ikke ForgeRock vært en realitet. Foredagsholderen vil beskrive hvordan tjener de penger på fri programvare. Presentasjonen vil også dekke generelle problemstillinger med Identity &amp; Access Management rundt områder som autentisering, autorisasjon, føderering og provisioning. Tidligere OpenSSO, nå OpenAM som de viderefører vil bli kort beskrevet sammen med resten av deres I3-platformstrategi. Stein Myrseth er Head of product Management hos ForgeRock. Hans rolle er å definere de videre strategiske retningslinjer for deres I3-strategi, samt</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214030100 +0000" stop="20230214030809 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Andrew Pelling: This scientist makes ears out of apples</title><desc lang="no">Andrew Pelling is a biohacker, and nature is his hardware. His favorite materials are the simplest ones (and oftentimes he finds them in the garbage). Building on the cellulose structure that gives an apple its shape, he &quot;grows&quot; lifelike human ears, pioneering a process that might someday be used to repair body parts safely and cheaply. And he has some even wilder ideas to share ... &quot;What I&apos;m really curious about is if one day it will be possible to repair, rebuild and augment our own bodies with stuff we make in the kitchen,&quot; he says. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214030900 +0000" stop="20230214035526 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Practical Protocol-Oriented Programming in Swift</title><desc lang="no">Value types are at the core of Swift (seriously, mostly everything in the Swift standard library is a value type). But how do you avoid subclassing? That&apos;s where the power of Protocol-Oriented programming comes in. Learn how to structure your code to (almost) never subclass again! Practical everyday examples and ideas for your own code base will be included. The speaker Natasha Murashev is an iOS developer by day and a robot by night. She blogs about Swift, WatchOS, and iOS development on her blog, natashatherobot.com, and curates a fast-growing weekly Swift newsletter: This Week in Swift. In her free time, she works on personal projects, speaks at meetups and conferences, contributes to open source, and likes to cross things off her bucket list. She&apos;s currently living the digital nomad life as her alter identity: @NatashaTheNomad.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214035600 +0000" stop="20230214041511 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Ken Robinson: How to escape education&apos;s death valley</title><desc lang="no">Sir Ken Robinson outlines 3 principles crucial for the human mind to flourish -- and how current education culture works against them. In a funny, stirring talk he tells us how to get out of the educational &quot;death valley&quot; we now face, and how to nurture our youngest generations with a climate of possibility. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214041600 +0000" stop="20230214052822 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Decentralized Open Source Mesh Networks - Benedict Lau</title><desc lang="no">Benedict Lau, en bidragsyter og arrangør på (Toronto Mesh), besøker oss for å snakke om å bygge nettverk for mesh-nettverk som er selvadresserende, desentralisert og fungerer uten internettforbindelse. Vi vil diskutere peer-to-peer-applikasjoner som det interplanetariske filsystemet (IPFS) og Secure Scuttlebutt (SSB), både teknisk og å utforske sosial dynamikk som oppstår når brukerne har eierskap og kontroll over webapplikasjonene de bruker. Foredraget vil gå på engelsk.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214052900 +0000" stop="20230214060929 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">EuroBSDCon 2019, Lillehammer: NUMA Optimizations in the FreeBSD Network Stack - Drew Gallatin</title><desc lang="no">will discuss optimizations to keep network connections and their resources local to NUMA domains. These changes include: Allocating NUMA local memory to back files sent via sendfile(9). Allocating NUMA local memory for Kernel TLS crypto buffers. Directing connections to TCP Pacers and kTLS workers bound to the local domain. Directing incoming connections to Nginx workers bound to the local domain via modifications to SO_REUSEPORT_LB listen sockets. I will present data from real Netflix servers showing an improvement of almost 2x on AMD EPYC (85Gbs - 165Gbs), and 1.3x on Intel Xeon (140Gb/s - 180Gbs). I will present data from the Xeon system showing a 50% reduction in cross-domain traffic. Drew Gallatin Drew started working on FreeBSD at Duke in the 90s, and was one of the people behind the FreeBSD/alpha port. He worked on zero-copy TCP optimizations for FreeBSD and was sending data at over 1Gb/s before gigabit Ethernet was generally available. He spent a decade at Myricom, optimizing their drivers. After a brief hiatus at Google, he landed at Netflix, where he works on optimizing the FreeBSD kernel and network stack for content delivery. He worked on the optimizations to serve unencrypted Netflix traffic at 100Gb/s, and then on more optimizations to send encrypted traffic at 100Gb/s.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214061000 +0000" stop="20230214064825 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Protest28AprilBaseavtaleUSA</title><desc lang="no">Appeller mot baseavtale med USA. Protest foran Stortinget 28. april 2022</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214064900 +0000" stop="20230214071524 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">MakerCon - Making the first Maker Faire in Sweden</title><desc lang="no">Nils Olander at MakerCon Nordic 2014-10-18. Video at the end is from https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=79IotXVypFs with music from https://soundcloud.com/nocopyrightsounds/tobu-itro-sunburst-ncs-release .</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214071600 +0000" stop="20230214073309 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Ernesto Sirolli: Want to help someone? Shut up and listen!</title><desc lang="no">When most well-intentioned aid workers hear of a problem they think they can fix, they go to work. This, Ernesto Sirolli suggests, is naïve. In this funny and impassioned talk, he proposes that the first step is to listen to the people you&apos;re trying to help, and tap into their own entrepreneurial spirit. His advice on what works will help any entrepreneur. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214073400 +0000" stop="20230214083645 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Erfaringer fra drift av sks-keyservers.net</title><desc lang="no">Kristian Fiskerstrand presenterer sine erfaringer med å utvikle og drive OpenPGP-nøkkeltjenere for utveksling av nøkler brukt til blant annet epostkryptering. Det vil være et særskilt fokus på DNS poolene på sks-keyservers.net - et prosjekt som ble startet av han i 2006 og i dag er brukt som standard nøkkeltjener av bl.a GnuPG. I tillegg til dette prosjektet er Kristian også en av utviklerne av nøkkeltjeneren SKS og Gentoo Developer med særlig fokus på Security og Crypto teamene.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214083700 +0000" stop="20230214085613 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Android SDK Tools in Debian - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">android-tools is a young packaging team which focuses on bringing a usable Android SDK/NDK to Debian. This talk describes the rationale, people involved and current status of our packages. We also would like to call for more people join us. Android one of the most popular mobile operating systems in the world, which also makes the SDK vital to us. However not every developer in the world can easily download Android&apos;s SDK. In some corner of the world, people prefer to rely on third party mirror or even developer-provided binaries on some web drives. XcodeGhost on iOS side was caused by similar reasons. Additionally, official released Android SDK binaries are proprietary software. By building the SDK from source and deploy it to all Debian mirrors spread over the world, all developers can easily get it and are safe to use it. The packaging force of Android SDK started as student projects of Google Summer of Code 2015 and 2016. Talk (20 mins) session with Kai-Chung Yan during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214085700 +0000" stop="20230214095112 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Egotripp - podcast på tv.</title><desc lang="no">Sommeren er på hell og Egotripp er tilbake. I høstens første episode møter Mattias sosialantropolog Thomas Hylland Eriksen. Det blir mye snakk om digitale hjelpemidler for to menn som nok lengter litt tilbake til det analoge: lp-plater, mobilfritt liv, og langsom tid.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214095200 +0000" stop="20230214101209 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond ali om Balfour-erklæringen</title><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214101300 +0000" stop="20230214103335 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">MakerCon - Making in Norway</title><desc lang="no">Haakon Karlsen Jr., Graham Hayward and Jens Dyvik at MakerCon Nordic 2014-10-17.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214103400 +0000" stop="20230214104257 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Dan Ariely: How equal do we want the world to be? You&apos;d be surprised</title><desc lang="no">The news of society&apos;s growing inequality makes all of us uneasy. But why? Dan Ariely reveals some new, surprising research on what we think is fair, as far as how wealth is distributed over societies ... then shows how it stacks up to the real stats. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214104300 +0000" stop="20230214113155 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Kali Linux&apos;s Experience of a Derivative Tracking Debian Testing - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">Kali Linux is a Debian derivative since 2012, it is maintained by Offensive Security and dedicated to penetration testing. Initially it was based on Debian Stable (Wheezy then Jessie) but since late 2015, it now tracks Debian Testing with its daily changes. There are upsides and downsides to this and I&apos;ll try to present those as well as the infrastructure that we have setup to run Kali Linux (repositories, build daemons, jenkins checks, etc.). This talk is interesting for other Debian derivatives that want to learn from Kali&apos;s experience, but it&apos;s also interesting for the Debian community to learn of the problems that derivatives are facing when they try to track Debian Testing. Talk (45 mins) session with Raphaël Hertzog during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214113200 +0000" stop="20230214115259 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">The Many ARMed Monster of Reproducibility - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">Describing the adventures building a build network of armhf machines to run reproducibility tests, using a variety of readily available consumer-grade boards to increase possible reproducibility problems due to hardware differences. I will endeavor to explain how it grew from a few cute machines into a (still a bit slow) monster. Rumours will be spread of other monsters lurking on the horizon. Comes complete with Colored Charts, Documented Side Effects, Power Consumption and Bandwidth figures, and 5-12 volt tentacle (mis)management, and perhaps most importantly, advice on avoiding (or falling prone to) the same fate yourself. Talk (20 mins) session with Vagrant Cascadian during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214115300 +0000" stop="20230214124808 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FiksGataMi - historie og tekno</title><desc lang="no">FiksGataMi er en tjeneste for borgerne i Norge for å synliggjøre problemer med offentlig infrastruktur, og gjøre det enkelt for innbyggerne å melde fra om slike problemer til offentlig myndighet. Presentasjonen vil fortelle litt om historien bak NUUG-prosjektet, hvordan systemet fungerer, og hvilke muligheter som finnes for å analysere og visualisere problemrapportene som er registrert i FiksGataMi.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214124900 +0000" stop="20230214130819 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Melissa Fleming: A boat carrying 500 refugees sunk at sea. The story of two survivors</title><desc lang="no">Aboard an overloaded ship carrying more than 500 refugees, a young woman becomes an unlikely hero. This single, powerful story, told by Melissa Fleming of the UN&apos;s refugee agency, gives a human face to the sheer numbers of human beings trying to escape to better lives ... as the refugee ships keep coming ... TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214130900 +0000" stop="20230214131648 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Christopher Soghoian: Your smartphone is a civil rights issue</title><desc lang="no">The smartphone you use reflects more than just personal taste ... it could determine how closely you can be tracked, too. Privacy expert and TED Fellow Christopher Soghoian details a glaring difference between the encryption used on Apple and Android devices and urges us to pay attention to a growing digital security divide. &quot;If the only people who can protect themselves from the gaze of the government are the rich and powerful, that&apos;s a problem,&quot; he says. &quot;It&apos;s not just a cybersecurity problem — it&apos;s a civil rights problem.&quot; TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214131700 +0000" stop="20230214140340 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">EuroBSDCon 2019, Lillehammer: Embedded Ethics - Patricia Aas</title><desc lang="no">Patricia is a programmer who has worked mostly in C++ and Java. She has spent her career continuously delivering from the same code-base to a large user base, from working on two browsers (Opera and Vivaldi), to working on embedded telepresence endpoints for Cisco. She is focused on the maintainability and flexibility of software architecture, and how to extend it to provide cutting edge user experiences. Her focus on the end users has led her work more and more toward privacy and security, and she has recently started her own company, TurtleSec, hoping to contribute positively to the infosec and C++ communities. She is also involved in the #includeC++ organization hoping to improve diversity and inclusion in the C++ community</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214140400 +0000" stop="20230214141518 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond Alis Kvarter - Anmeldelse av Midtøsten på 200 sider, og Arab and Jew in the land of Canaan</title><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214141600 +0000" stop="20230214142124 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Nancy Lublin: Texting that saves lives</title><desc lang="no">When Nancy Lublin started texting teenagers to help with her social advocacy organization, what she found was shocking -- they started texting back about their own problems, from bullying to depression to abuse. So she&apos;s setting up a text-only crisis line, and the results might be even more important than she expected. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214142200 +0000" stop="20230214144431 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Sugata Mitra: Build a School in the Cloud</title><desc lang="no">Onstage at TED2013, Sugata Mitra makes his bold TED Prize wish: Help me design the School in the Cloud, a learning lab in India, where children can explore and learn from each other -- using resources and mentoring from the cloud. Hear his inspiring vision for Self Organized Learning Environments (SOLE), and learn more at tedprize.org. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive on https://archive.org/details/SugataMitra_2013</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214144500 +0000" stop="20230214152336 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Bits from the DPL - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">State of the project, ongoing activities and planned changes Talk (45 mins) session with Mehdi Dogguy during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214152400 +0000" stop="20230214152956 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Greg Gage: How to control someone else&apos;s arm with your brain</title><desc lang="no">Greg Gage is on a mission to make brain science accessible to all. In this fun, kind of creepy demo, the neuroscientist and TED Senior Fellow uses a simple, inexpensive DIY kit to take away the free will of an audience member. It’s not a parlor trick; it actually works. You have to see it to believe it. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214153000 +0000" stop="20230214160851 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Gustav Eek - Communication Infrastructure - a form of resistance</title><desc lang="no">In this lecture the democratic principles of Fripost, the free email association (founded in 2010) will be presented. Infrastructure for electronic communication will be resembled with a common good (a resource). That using a critique of the public–private dichotomy, and the tragedy of the commons. I will then demonstrate how also complicated resources can (and must) be made subject to democratic control. The importance of Internet as communication medium can not be questioned. For those who take user freedom seriously it is saddening to see how the Internet has changed from being a common and highly distributed network to the increasingly privatised web we encounter today. In this lecture I will present the democratic principles of Fripost, the free email association which was founded as a reaction to that development. I will resemble infrastructure for electronic communication with a common good (a resource), and I will demonstrate how also complicated resources can (and must) be made subject to democratic control. Fripost and its foundation and democratic principals has been presented several times since its constitution in 2010, also at FSCONS. This is why the lecture also will take a different and broader stand, inspired by some recent readings. The Fripost initative will also be put in context of local struggles with global implication. In short, the idea that every resource needs an single responsible and managing owner is unsatisfactory as well as the dichotomy public–private. What is not managed can not yield profit. But some things are to important even to be managed. Naturally this touches on a critique (which has been presented many times before) of Hardin’s classical tragedy of the commons. Regarding the enclosure of the commons, management in it self causes the scarcity, The commons are not scarce resources that requires management. See ref url for further details. Recorded by NUUG for FSCONS.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214160900 +0000" stop="20230214163230 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Debian/Linux in Developing Nations - Challenges and Rewards - Debconf 16</title><desc lang="no">FOSS software is undoubtedly the best option for developing nations, where financial resources may limit access to proprietary software. At the same time, using Debian/Linux also has its share of challenges in these settings, as there may be infrastructure issues to contend with. This talk shares the joys I have personally experienced while using Debian in Swaziland, as well as the challenges that I have faced, and also seen others face too. Perhaps the audience may be able to suggest ways to overcome some of the issues involved, and thus get more exposure and adoption for Debian in developing countries. Talk (20 mins) session with Sicelo Mhlongo during Debconf 16</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214163300 +0000" stop="20230214164743 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Michael Green: How we can make the world a better place by 2030</title><desc lang="no">Can we end hunger and poverty, halt climate change and achieve gender equality in the next 15 years? The governments of the world think we can. Meeting at the UN in September 2015, they agreed to a new set of Global Goals for the development of the world to 2030. Social progress expert Michael Green invites us to imagine how these goals and their vision for a better world can be achieved. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214164800 +0000" stop="20230214165552 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Conference Opening</title><desc lang="no">Kacper Why and Thomas Gramstad introduce the FSCONS 2017 conference. Recorded by NUUG for FSCONS.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214165600 +0000" stop="20230214165635 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Infoplakat Frikanalen</title><desc lang="no">Informasjon om Frikanalen</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214165700 +0000" stop="20230214165819 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Kopiering er ikke tyveri</title><category lang="no">Barn og ungdom</category><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214165900 +0000" stop="20230214165948 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Frikanalen Informasjonsfilm</title><desc lang="no">Info!</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214170000 +0000" stop="20230214175814 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Gud, Jehova, Jesus og Den Hellige Ånd</title><desc lang="no">De er forskjellige forteller bibelen</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214175900 +0000" stop="20230214183650 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Pål Taule Bentebråten - Towards a Global Cryptocurrency Infrastructure: A Revolutionary Sharing Economy</title><desc lang="no">Yesterday we bartered with favors. If you do something for me, I will do something for you in return. Today giant tech companies has commercialised the favor for a favor economy. They have built strong platforms with algorithms to match two parties in a market. Uber matches drivers with people that need a ride, AirBnB matches people that are in need of a place to stay with people that are renting out their apartments. They call this the sharing economy, but there is no such thing as sharing in it. Tomorrow, we will build the true sharing economy on decentralized platforms that is owned by the people and not giant tech corporations. We will build platforms where the value is not extracted by a third party, but distributed right back into the network. We will build bottom up organizations with structures of collaboration and sharing rather than top down hierarchies of command and control. * A brief history of the sharing economy * How the sharing economy works today * How blockchain can transform the sharing economy * Hurdles ahead, challenges of using blockchains * Think big, think ahead, see a world of opportunities How cryptocurrencies can enable a true sharing economy. Challenges ahead: Infrastructure and global adoption Regulation vs Innovation What’s next? Universal Basic Income (UBI) A decentralized Internet Nexus Filmed by NUUG for FSCONS.</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214183700 +0000" stop="20230214185306 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Nathalie Cabrol: How Mars might hold the secret to the origin of life</title><desc lang="no">While we like to imagine little green men, it’s far more likely that life on other planets will be microbial. Planetary scientist Nathalie Cabrol takes us inside the search for microbes on Mars, a hunt which counterintuitively leads us to the remote lakes of the Andes mountains. This extreme environment — with its thin atmosphere and scorched land — approximates the surface of Mars about 3.5 billion years ago. How microbes adapt to survive here may just show us where to look on Mars — and could help us understand why some microbial pathways lead to civilization while others are a dead end. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214185400 +0000" stop="20230214185702 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Anne Cath. Vestlys 100-årsjubileum</title><desc lang="no">I år ville forfatteren Anne Cath. Vestly fylt 100 år. Empo var på plass da dagen ble feiret i forfatterens fødeby, nemlig Rena.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214185800 +0000" stop="20230214185943 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Annerledes av Margrete</title><desc lang="no">Margrete (33) har skrevet og framført et dikt om å leve med en funksjonshemming. Selv har hun asperger-syndrom.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214190000 +0000" stop="20230214190748 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Jerusalem! Uro og opprør der</title><desc lang="no">Jerusalem! Uro og opprør der</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214190800 +0000" stop="20230214192408 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Alice Goffman: How we&apos;re priming some kids for college — and others for prison</title><desc lang="no">In the United States, two institutions guide teenagers on the journey to adulthood: college and prison. Sociologist Alice Goffman spent six years in a troubled Philadelphia neighborhood and saw first-hand how teenagers of African-American and Latino backgrounds are funneled down the path to prison — sometimes starting with relatively minor infractions. In an impassioned talk she asks, “Why are we offering only handcuffs and jail time?” TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214192500 +0000" stop="20230214194730 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Monica Lewinsky: The price of shame</title><desc lang="no">&quot;Public shaming as a blood sport has to stop,&quot; says Monica Lewinsky. In 1998, she says, “I was Patient Zero of losing a personal reputation on a global scale almost instantaneously.” Today, the kind of online public shaming she went through has become constant — and can turn deadly. In a brave talk, she takes a hard look at our online culture of humiliation, and asks for a different way. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214194800 +0000" stop="20230214195407 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Venn av Nøff</title><desc lang="no">Det er høst og tid for Nasse Nøff å komme inn i varmen etter en lang sesong ute i hagen. Søndag 2.november hadde foreningen Venn av Nøff sin årlige innbæring. I tillegg blir det utdeling av NÆ!-prisen. Følg med.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214195500 +0000" stop="20230214195914 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Palestinske høytider</title><desc lang="no">Trond Ali og Hanan snakker om palestinske høytider</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214200000 +0000" stop="20230214204100 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Økt spenning i nordområdene</title><desc lang="no">Temaer som berøres er: Økt militarisering og spenning i nordområdene; Farer ved atomvåpen og opprustning; Norges rolle knyttet til militarisering og allianse- (NATO) og sikkerhetspolitikk</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214204200 +0000" stop="20230214215645 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Data collection, psychometric profiling and their impact on politics</title><desc lang="no">Most political campaigns are data-driven nowadays, and many are getting into profiling of individual voters. Recently, a company with a strong background in military PSYOPS has implemented technology developed at Cambridge University, to enable psychological profiling based on digital traces. They have then been embedded into some of the most surprising recent political campaigns: Ted Cruz&apos;s, Donald Trump&apos;s and Leave.EU (Brexit). I will outline my personal journey, first discovering the technology as a test subject for Cambridge University, then investigating this company as a complete amateur, and eventually contributing to an article shared globally. A background article based on this research was published by NRK Beta early in february 2017, see &lt;https://nrkbeta.no/2017/02/04/dataene-som-snudde-verden-pa-hodet/&gt;. The speaker, Paul-Olivier Dehaye, is a mathematician at the University of Zurich working on interoperability tools enabling new forms of collaborative work on mathematical data, knowledge and software. In his spare time, he enjoys litigating (and especially winning!) against multibillion dollar businesses for the defence of his fundamental right to data protection. He is now leveraging that experience as co-founder of PersonalData.IO, a service that helps individuals regain control over their personal data. NUUG talk from 2017-04-04.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214215700 +0000" stop="20230214224929 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Stopp NATO 5. november 2022, del 1</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214225000 +0000" stop="20230214225744 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Søt, sexy, godt, morsom</title><desc lang="no">Hvorfor er babyer søte? Hvorfor er kake godt? Filosof Dan Dennett har svar du ikke forventer, der han gir oss evolusjonens ikke-intuitive forklaring på søte, gode og sexy ting (i tillegg til en ny teori fra Matthew Hurley om hvorfor vitser er morsomme).</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214225800 +0000" stop="20230214225835 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Infoplakat Frikanalen</title><desc lang="no">Informasjon om Frikanalen</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230214225900 +0000" stop="20230214225948 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Frikanalen Informasjonsfilm</title><desc lang="no">Info!</desc><category lang="no">Andre</category></programme>
<programme start="20230215153000 +0000" stop="20230215162700 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Daily Tech News Show 21. September 2016</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230215170000 +0000" stop="20230215175602 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Kong Salomo og hva HAN mener</title><desc lang="no">Kong Salomo er verdens klokeste mann</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230215190000 +0000" stop="20230215190708 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond Alis kvarter XXIII</title><desc lang="no">Trond Ali kommenterer samisk nasjonaldag 2</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230215203000 +0000" stop="20230215205357 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Shofar Gud setter konger av og konger inn</title><desc lang="no">program 149, bladet evangelisten</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230216150000 +0000" stop="20230216150302 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Anne Cath. Vestlys 100-årsjubileum</title><desc lang="no">I år ville forfatteren Anne Cath. Vestly fylt 100 år. Empo var på plass da dagen ble feiret i forfatterens fødeby, nemlig Rena.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230216151500 +0000" stop="20230216151802 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Anne Cath. Vestlys 100-årsjubileum</title><desc lang="no">I år ville forfatteren Anne Cath. Vestly fylt 100 år. Empo var på plass da dagen ble feiret i forfatterens fødeby, nemlig Rena.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230216153000 +0000" stop="20230216162656 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Daily Tech News Show 28. April 2016</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230216170000 +0000" stop="20230216175602 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Kong Salomo og hva HAN mener</title><desc lang="no">Kong Salomo er verdens klokeste mann</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230216190000 +0000" stop="20230216191233 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Har USA og NATO framprovosert krigen i Ukraina</title><desc lang="no">Har USA og NATO framprovosert krigen i Ukraina</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230216200000 +0000" stop="20230216202649 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Stopp NATO 5. november 2022, del 3</title><desc lang="no">Del tre - foredrag med Geir Hem</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230217153000 +0000" stop="20230217162519 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Daily Tech News Show 19. May 2016</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230217163000 +0000" stop="20230217164542 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Wendy Freedman: This new telescope might show us the beginning of the universe</title><desc lang="no">When and how did the universe begin? A global group of astronomers wants to answer that question by peering as far back in time as a large new telescope will let us see. Wendy Freedman headed the creation of the Giant Magellan Telescope, under construction in South America; at TEDGlobal in Rio, she shares a bold vision of the discoveries about our universe that the GMT could make possible. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230217170000 +0000" stop="20230217175928 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Fortid, nåtid og framtid</title><desc lang="no">Det glemmer jeg aldri</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230217190000 +0000" stop="20230217190843 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Trond Alis kvarter XXI</title><desc lang="no">Trond Ali snakker om hvordan Holocaust blir misbrukt</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218110000 +0000" stop="20230218115928 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Fortid, nåtid og framtid</title><desc lang="no">Det glemmer jeg aldri</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218120000 +0000" stop="20230218131230 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">(1) Nyheter om Jehovas Vitner &amp; Vakttårnet</title><desc lang="no">Egil S. Langemyr</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218133000 +0000" stop="20230218133633 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">TED - Leah Buechley: How to “sketch” with electronics</title><desc lang="no">Designing electronics is generally cumbersome and expensive -- or was, until Leah Buechley and her team at MIT developed tools to treat electronics just like paper and pen. In this talk from TEDYouth 2011, Buechley shows some of her charming designs, like a paper piano you can sketch and then play. Background music by DJ Shadow. TED talk downloaded from The Internet Archive.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218150000 +0000" stop="20230218150302 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Anne Cath. Vestlys 100-årsjubileum</title><desc lang="no">I år ville forfatteren Anne Cath. Vestly fylt 100 år. Empo var på plass da dagen ble feiret i forfatterens fødeby, nemlig Rena.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218151500 +0000" stop="20230218151802 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Anne Cath. Vestlys 100-årsjubileum</title><desc lang="no">I år ville forfatteren Anne Cath. Vestly fylt 100 år. Empo var på plass da dagen ble feiret i forfatterens fødeby, nemlig Rena.</desc><category lang="no">Kultur</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218153000 +0000" stop="20230218162031 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Daily Tech News Show 19. September 2016</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218170000 +0000" stop="20230218175849 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Profeten Daniel og framtiden</title><desc lang="no">Nyttige og interessante opplysninger om framtiden</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230218190000 +0000" stop="20230218191244 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Nazistenes folkemord på romani-folket (sigøynerne)</title><desc lang="no">Nazistenes folkemord på romani-folket (sigøynerne)</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230219103000 +0000" stop="20230219105357 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Shofar Gud setter konger av og konger inn</title><desc lang="no">program 149, bladet evangelisten</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230219130000 +0000" stop="20230219131712 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">FSCONS 2017 - Joakim Lundborg - Why we need free password managers</title><desc lang="no">This talk will be about my experience building uis for the pass password manager, and some related concerns: * Why usability is a security feature *The need for free software password manages * Can this be a path to drive GPG adoption? Recorded by NUUG for FSCONS. https://github.com/cortex/gopass https://github.com/cortex/ripasso Recorded for FSCONS by NUUG.</desc><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230219170000 +0000" stop="20230219175814 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Gud, Jehova, Jesus og Den Hellige Ånd</title><desc lang="no">De er forskjellige forteller bibelen</desc><category lang="no">Religion/livssyn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230219180000 +0000" stop="20230219185250 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Daily Tech News Show 25. July 2016</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
<programme start="20230219190000 +0000" stop="20230219191827 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Krigen i Ukraina. En mulig løsning</title><desc lang="no">Krigen i Ukraina. En mulig løsning</desc><category lang="no">Solidaritet og bistand</category></programme>
<programme start="20230219200000 +0000" stop="20230219202349 +0000" channel="Frikanalen.no"><title lang="no">Galtung spår 911 rett før det skjedde</title><category lang="no">Samfunn</category></programme>
</tv>