<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><tv date="20230213">
<channel id="IONPlusEast.us"><display-name>ION Plus East</display-name><icon src="https://i.imgur.com/1dgCvNE.png"/><url>https://ionplustv.com</url></channel>
<programme start="20230213100000 +0000" stop="20230213103000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Weekend Reno</title><sub-title lang="en">109 : Karen, Bill And Andrea Felstead</sub-title><desc lang="en">Bill has a sentimental attachment to the cottage he helped build with his father and is reluctant to change a thing, despite the fact that wife Karen and daughter Andrea feel it&apos;s stuck in a time warp. With Michelle and her team in for the weekend, Bill gets the nudge he needs to finally see the transformation from a dark, dreary basement into a bright, welcoming walk-out. A collection of worn couches and the putting-green like carpet are replaced with a cozy, modernized seating area, a custom bar and new flooring, which garners a BIG reaction from the cottage owners!</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/weekend-reno/show-banner-weekend-reno-5ab164883416d-8c2709efae74208d968468a1239fd82cd0fef149.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213103000 +0000" stop="20230213110000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Weekend Reno</title><sub-title lang="en">110 : Norma, Christyn And Ron Oda</sub-title><desc lang="en">Renovation projects stalled over ten years ago due to an illness in the family, which also prompted owners Norma and Ron to spend time enjoying the cottage rather than laboring over it. Daughter Christyn called in the Weekend Reno team to finally complete this work-in-progress. After Anthony takes time out to go fishing, he realizes there are no free lunches and pays for it with extra-long days of flooring and finish carpentry work. And Merrill tackles some special projects of her own, while Michelle scours a local flea market for stand-out pieces to bring the design together.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/weekend-reno/show-banner-weekend-reno-5ab164e60620d-b8d51271f7b0db273e7639cf05d841682b6f0a24.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213110000 +0000" stop="20230213113000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Bake With Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">203 : Flourless Cakes</sub-title><desc lang="en">Cakes made without using flour are actually quite common, and have long been appreciated before the days of gluten-free living. This episode showcases some classic and contemporary cakes made using ingredients other than flour (commonly found ingredients) and with that comes the lesson in how to achieve delicate and moist cakes made without wheat flour. i. Italian Blood Orange Syrup Cake “ Ground almonds lend structure to this Cake that highlights a fragrant orange flavour and shine from the syrup poured over the warm cake. ii. French Flourless Chocolate Torte “ This is a traditional, rich and moist chocolate cake that relies on whipped eggs and chocolate to give it a moist interior and crunchy exterior. iii. Flourless Vanilla Cupcakes “ Those baking without flour often need a classic flourless cake recipe that suits a birthday party, and this fits the bill.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/bake-with-anna-olson/show-banner-bake-with-anna-olson-5b7dcecb89d73-16203668ab1f7ab0aff277fa6e573964d57b810f.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213113000 +0000" stop="20230213120000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Bake With Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">204 : Biscotti</sub-title><desc lang="en">A staple cookie in most coffee shops, biscotti (which translates from Italian to mean twice baked) share a common technique, but that results in a variety of end results. From the classic crunchy biscotti to a more tender version, along with a cross application, everything you need to know about biscotti is explained. i. Classic Almond Cranberry Biscotti - these are the traditional, super-crunchy biscotti, perfect for dunking into coffee. They are large and look just like the ones you see at a coffee shop counter, in a big jar. ii. Tender Chocolate Cantucci - Cantucci (also cantuccini} are a variation of biscotti, but differentiated by their tender, more delicate texture. These suit more of a cookie tin and take a little more refined technique in order to achieve the softer texture. iii. Biscotti Ricotta Cheesecake - appreciating biscotti as a pastry chef includes using it as a component in a fancier dessert. In this recipe, biscotti is crushed to make the crust and also adds flavour to an Italian st</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/bake-with-anna-olson/show-banner-bake-with-anna-olson-5b7dc8894c879-5ce190ead41b066e8387d7ce6fae3c759250ec7b.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213120000 +0000" stop="20230213123000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Bake With Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">205 : Bars</sub-title><desc lang="en">In terms of technique, bars don&apos;t have technical qualifications that distinguish them from squares (other than the shape) but as a widely popular baked treat, there are many options to showcase, from healthy granola bars to decadent Nanaimo Bars and Caramel Chocolate Candy Bars. The lessons within making the bars are worthwhile and bars are second only to cookies in popularity in the home baker&apos;s kitchen. A relative of the favourite &quot;squareÂ·, bars are typically cut into rectangle portions to earn their name. This episode showcases a number of traditional favourites, from a simple, one-bowl granola bar recipe to a distinctly Canadian Nanaimo Bar. i. Traditional Granola Bars - this recipe is a good place to start the lesson, since a granola bar is a single-layer bar (no crust or topping). Full of nutritious grains, nuts, seeds and fruits, these are a healthy treat. ii. Nanaimo Bars - A more elaborate, dessert-like bar, Nanaimo bars have a chocolate crust with a signature custard filling and are topped</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/bake-with-anna-olson/show-banner-bake-with-anna-olson-5b7dc0cd4dab8-a8f3c523394b3921407d0c7643d0244c8d457106.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213123000 +0000" stop="20230213130000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Bake With Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">206 : Caramel</sub-title><desc lang="en">Who doesn&apos;t love caramel? Learning to make a basic caramel opens the patisserie door to just so many desserts and delights, from classic to creative. i. Classic Caramel/Caramel Apples - The principles behind making a traditional caramel is shown here, and then is used to dip apples. ii. French Apple Tarte Tatin -Another more advanced application for caramel is seen in this classic French version of apple pie. Sugar is caramelized in a heavy skillet and then apples are added. Topped with puff pastry, the tart bakes upside down, and then is served with the apples and now built-in caramel sauce on top. iii. French Creme Caramel - This classic showcases caramel at its most elegant. Caramelized sugar is poured into dishes to set, then topped with a silky custard base that is baked. Once inverted, it is revealed that the caramel softens and makes a sauce that keeps this dessert consistently on bistro menus.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/bake-with-anna-olson/show-banner-bake-with-anna-olson-5b7dccb6ddb7a-1f980f024d987a2aa84cfd3fb0a734368ab30618.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213130000 +0000" stop="20230213133000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Bake With Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">207 : Pate Sucree</sub-title><desc lang="en">Sugar pastry differs in texture and taste from a Sablee pastry and is equally valued in a pastry kitchen sugar. Sugar pastry (known as pate sucree) is a little more delicate and fragile due to its higher sugar and butter content, so suits fillings of an according texture. This episode defines this, shows how to achieve and use this delicate pastry, and of course includes tips and tricks to make it even more versatile. i. Basic Sugar Dough and Snickerdoodle Cookies - the basic sugar dough formula can also be baked into snickerdoodle cookies: drop cookies rolled in cinnamon sugar before baking. ii. Frangipan Tart - a sweet almond filling is a traditional choice to bake into a tender sugar dough shell. Here we get a sense of rolling and baking the now-chilled dough and making and baking the traditional filling. iii. Blackberry Meringue Tarts - Sugar dough gets dressed up - the pastry can hold a filling, but brushing the inside of the tart shell with white chocolate prevents it from absorbing the blackbe</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/bake-with-anna-olson/show-banner-bake-with-anna-olson-5b7dccb6ddb7a-1f980f024d987a2aa84cfd3fb0a734368ab30618.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213133000 +0000" stop="20230213140000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Bake With Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">208 : Marzipan</sub-title><desc lang="en">Marzipan is made simply from ground almonds mixed with sugar to achieve a paste, but it has so many uses in the dessert world. This episode showcases marzipan from its fundamental creation to its many uses. i. Homemade Marzipan - master the formula for a tasty and easy-to-handle marzipan. This can be shaped into little candies, topped with a toasted almond. ii. Easy Marzipan Fruitcakes - Individual fruitcakes are made using marzipan within the batter and rolled to top the fruitcakes. Can include dried mango in the fruit mix (have just tested the recipe and would be a lovely addition) iii. Classic Battenberg Cake - Ever have high tea at the Empress Hotel in Victoria? Then you know that this checkerboard cake batter is made using marzipan, and then covered with a coloured marzipan for this English classic served at afternoon tea.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/bake-with-anna-olson/show-banner-bake-with-anna-olson-5b7dc0cd4dab8-a8f3c523394b3921407d0c7643d0244c8d457106.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213140000 +0000" stop="20230213160000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Midsomer Murders</title><sub-title lang="en">0603 : Painted in Blood</sub-title><desc lang="en">Joyce joins the local watercolour society for an open-air art class on the village green in Midsomer Florey. Shortly before taking a break, she stumbles across the body of elderly Ruth Fairfax, a fellow artist. It turns out there was more to Ruth than met the eye. Barnaby is taken off the case by the National Intelligence Squad and it is left to Troy to &apos;apprehensively&apos; keep Barnaby informed on the investigation. Barnaby and Troy soon uncover that the proceeds from an armed robbery are missing. They find out all information about former criminals alongside all the secret liaisons, before they bring all the culprits to justice.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/midsomer-murders/show-banner-midsomer-murders-63b848fcc84c7-47c6787a04f9f659e81298afc1601eba7c28a590.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14 D,L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213160000 +0000" stop="20230213180000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Midsomer Murders</title><sub-title lang="en">0604 : A Tale Of Two Hamlets</sub-title><desc lang="en">At the family home of actor Larry Smith in the village of Upper Warden, a crowd has gathered to watch the promotion for the sequel to his hit film, &apos;The House of Satan&apos;, when Larry walks into a summer house on the grounds that suddenly explodes. His family quickly suggest that it was someone from the rival village of Lower Warden. When Larry&apos;s director, another member of his family, is also murdered, electrocuted while using an exercise bike, DCI Barnaby and DS Troy deal with affairs and secrets, alongside blackmail, to find the reason why.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/midsomer-murders/show-banner-midsomer-murders-63b848fcc84c7-47c6787a04f9f659e81298afc1601eba7c28a590.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14 D,L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213180000 +0000" stop="20230213190000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">105 : Haunted By The Past</sub-title><desc lang="en">When a controversial university professor is found dead in his classroom, Charlie and Rex investigate leads while Jesse goes undercover and soon finds himself danger.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-636121891da8d-b8c3c76559008a834d13de150b8d8592c3eb94a0.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213190000 +0000" stop="20230213200000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">103 : School Days</sub-title><desc lang="en">The animal lovers of St. John&apos;s are under suspicion as Charlie and Rex investigate the death of a professional pet sitter. At home, Charlie finds himself in need of Sarah&apos;s help.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-6361218d6765f-d13e372260fdd10793e886f2ff8bba104dc5ff3f.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14 L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213200000 +0000" stop="20230213210000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">104 : The Pet Sitter</sub-title><desc lang="en">When a woman is found comatose in a graveyard, Charlie and Rex dig up a cold case which may be connected. Donovan asks Charlie to spy on his daughter after she begins acting suspiciously.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-63612182ae3b2-8751ceeed5e620a6aa7debe5c002ad0d9a895a13.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213210000 +0000" stop="20230213220000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">108 : Murder, She Thought</sub-title><desc lang="en">After a reviled restaurateur&apos;s food truck explodes, killing one of his employees, Charlie and Rex find themselves with a few too many suspects. A flirtation has Charlie torn between a possible new love interest and Rex, who makes no secret of his feelings on the matter.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-636121891da8d-b8c3c76559008a834d13de150b8d8592c3eb94a0.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213220000 +0000" stop="20230213230000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">109 : Trial And Error</sub-title><desc lang="en">Sarah winds up in a hostage situation at a medical testing lab, and the team sends Rex in to help.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-636121891da8d-b8c3c76559008a834d13de150b8d8592c3eb94a0.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230213230000 +0000" stop="20230214000000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">106 : Fast Eddie&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">When the pharmacist at Charlie&apos;s aunt&apos;s retirement home is found dead, she alerts him to a mysterious string of recent fatalities among the home&apos;s residents.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-636121891da8d-b8c3c76559008a834d13de150b8d8592c3eb94a0.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14 L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214000000 +0000" stop="20230214010000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">113 : The Mourning Show</sub-title><desc lang="en">Sarah finds herself in the middle of a hostage situation at a medical testing lab. When the team realizes there&apos;s no way inside without aggravating the gunman, Charlie sends Rex in to monitor the situation.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-6361218d6765f-d13e372260fdd10793e886f2ff8bba104dc5ff3f.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG D,S,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214010000 +0000" stop="20230214020000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">107 : Art Of Darkness</sub-title><desc lang="en">Charlie and Rex investigate a hot case under cold conditions when a figure skating coach is found dead on her club&apos;s ice rink.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-63612182ae3b2-8751ceeed5e620a6aa7debe5c002ad0d9a895a13.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214020000 +0000" stop="20230214030000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">111 : Bad Water Rising</sub-title><desc lang="en">When an activist is killed during a break-and-enter at a water bottling plant, all evidence points towards his partner-in-crime, but Charlie and Rex aren&apos;t convinced.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-63612182ae3b2-8751ceeed5e620a6aa7debe5c002ad0d9a895a13.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214030000 +0000" stop="20230214040000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">114 : A Cult Education</sub-title><desc lang="en">Charlie and Rex discover a wanted criminal has been living in St. John&apos;s under a false identity for twenty years and end up in the crosshairs when the man&apos;s past catches up with him.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-63612182ae3b2-8751ceeed5e620a6aa7debe5c002ad0d9a895a13.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214040000 +0000" stop="20230214050000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">115 : The Rex Files</sub-title><desc lang="en">Charlie investigates the host of a local morning show after her media mogul husband is suddenly found dead.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-636121891da8d-b8c3c76559008a834d13de150b8d8592c3eb94a0.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214050000 +0000" stop="20230214060000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">HUDSON &amp; REX</title><sub-title lang="en">112 : Man Of Consequence</sub-title><desc lang="en">When Donovan&apos;s ex, a recovering addict, wakes up with blood on her hands and a dead roommate in her apartment, the team moves quickly, finding there&apos;s more to the story.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/hudson-rex/show-banner-hudson-rex-636121891da8d-b8c3c76559008a834d13de150b8d8592c3eb94a0.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14 V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214060000 +0000" stop="20230214070000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">All For Nothing?</title><sub-title lang="en">210 : Nicki &amp; Tori Vs. Angela &amp; Dave</sub-title><desc lang="en">Nicki, with sister Tori at her side, is tasked with transforming the dorm dÃ©cor in her starter home to a buyer-friendly design. Penny&apos;s plans are more than these sisters can handle so they enlist their handy dad to help. With a skilled team in place, Nicki gets a jump on painting, landscaping, and flooring; however, a medical hurdle threatens to derail their progress. Nicki must now rely on friends and family more than ever to get the job done. Competitors, Angela and Dave need their home to reach its full potential in order to realize Angela&apos;s dream of owning a pool. Sourcing granite countertops in the first couple days is a huge achievement, but with little reno savoir-faire, Dave is dependent on skilled friends to make headway on the DIY projects. Angela turns her clutter into cash but it&apos;s not enough to convince the couple to move forward with Penny&apos;s lavish deck design. Now, with the house of their dreams (complete with in-ground pool) fresh on the market, Angela and Dave are determined to take</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/all-for-nothing/show-banner-all-for-nothing-5ab162f2d8ee6-897aca6d7d9a7d4e2026ca3b592d8b2a047238fa.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG+L</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214070000 +0000" stop="20230214080000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">All For Nothing?</title><sub-title lang="en">211 : Brigitte &amp; Dave Vs. Peter &amp; Shelagh</sub-title><desc lang="en">Homeowners, Brigitte and Dave moved into their fixer-upper planning to do the renovations themselves. Eight years later, only a fraction of their projects are complete. With a new home already purchased, Brigitte and Dave need to get their current house market ready “ fast! With a dated kitchen, pink carpet and a bathroom in need of a total gut job, Brigitte and Dave have their work cut out for them. Brigitte wastes no time on the fundraising front, hosting a fitness dance class event and silent auction but as tricky projects present unexpected challenges and delays, reno expenses soar and workmanship plummets. Competitors, Peter and Shelagh have discovered the meaning of &quot;house poor?. These newlyweds have already moved into a new home; however, they&apos;re still carrying the mortgage on Peter&apos;s house from a previous marriage. Peter&apos;s former home appears abandoned”with empty bedrooms, half-finished projects, a kitchen and bathroom stuck in a time warp, it&apos;ll take a whole lot of elbow grease to get</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/all-for-nothing/show-banner-all-for-nothing-5ab162f2d8ee6-897aca6d7d9a7d4e2026ca3b592d8b2a047238fa.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG+L</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214080000 +0000" stop="20230214090000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">All For Nothing?</title><sub-title lang="en">212 : Lucille &amp; Natalie Vs. Paula &amp; Josh</sub-title><desc lang="en">Originally bought as a fixer upper, Lucille&apos;s home quickly became a whole home renovation, including: a decrepit entrance way, a front room used as storage, a half-finished kitchen, a living room in dire need of an update and a bathroom gut job. Lucille recruits her daughter Natalie to help out, and armed with Penny and Paul&apos;s advice, the mother-daughter team get going on demolition. Both handy, Lucille and Natalie show off their quality workmanship and work together harmoniously to get the job down. Help from friends and family brings Lucille that much closer to her goal, but will a community bake sale raise enough to cover their high end finishes? Across town a rivalry brews, as comedian Josh attempts to pay-back his mom, Homeowner Paula, for her financial support as he built his career. Paula&apos;s small city, home is in complete disrepair and features a few wacky personal touches”a clothesline through the kitchen, Safari and Asian themed rooms and exterior siding that covers over a window”that must</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/all-for-nothing/show-banner-all-for-nothing-5ab162f2d8ee6-897aca6d7d9a7d4e2026ca3b592d8b2a047238fa.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG+L</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214090000 +0000" stop="20230214100000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">All For Nothing?</title><sub-title lang="en">213 : Chris &amp; Cherry Vs. Matthew &amp; Michelle</sub-title><desc lang="en">With plans to start a family, homeowners Chris and Cherry, have already bought a new home. The problem is their forest green carpets, awkward staging, outdated kitchen, and unconventional colour choices are dragging down the sale price of their current home. Chris and Cherry make up for their lack of reno experience by assembling a savvy team of friends to help out. Chris is applauded for successfully using a power drill and Cherry gets a paint lesson from her sister-in-law but at the halfway mark, Paul and Penny are shocked to discover that they haven&apos;t raised a dime to cover their reno costs. How will the lack of fundraising affect their chances in the boardroom? With four young boys, competitors Matthew and Michelle have outgrown their cramped, suburban townhome. Paul and Penny suggest a tile upgrade to the linoleum on the main level, as well as updates in the kitchen and main bathroom, neutralizing the paint in the boys&apos; room and de-cluttering”including removing the treadmill from the dining room! M</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/all-for-nothing/show-banner-all-for-nothing-5ab162f5da8f4-562306ed3f0d96be256753a473699ae2974478bb.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG+L</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214100000 +0000" stop="20230214110000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">All For Nothing?</title><sub-title lang="en">214 : Trisha &amp; Alec Vs. Betts &amp; Samantha</sub-title><desc lang="en">As Trisha prepares for an empty nest, she teams up with her son Alec one more time to un-do years of damage to a home that was party central for Alec and all his friends growing up. They kick start the competition with a shock and awe approach with a strong turnout by Alec&apos;s buddies to tackle the demolition work. But can these unskilled hands put the house back together? A self-professed handy woman, Betts gets additional support from her daughter Samantha. But keeping a family commitment on day one means delaying the start to their reno projects. With only two weeks to get the job done this is a significant setback, but a steady stream of helpers that include Betts&apos; father, her other children and neighbours slowly keep the renos moving forward. Will the tortoise overcome the hare in this rivalry between Mother-son and Mother-daughter?</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/all-for-nothing/show-banner-all-for-nothing-5ab162f2d8ee6-897aca6d7d9a7d4e2026ca3b592d8b2a047238fa.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG+L</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214110000 +0000" stop="20230214113000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Fresh with Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">1025 : Spanish Tapas</sub-title><desc lang="en">Anna&apos;s preparing a meal of traditional Spanish Tapas “ small portions perfect for sharing with friends. She uses a variety of different flavours and textures to make dishes such as Spanish Pinxos, Potato Tortilla with Chorizo Sausage, San Sebastian Crab Tarts and Gambas a la Plancha “ little bites with big results!</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/fresh-with-anna-olson/show-banner-fresh-with-anna-olson-5952cd03c208d-99add9fc13da143f3f95289a2c0be90e82a1ac92.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214113000 +0000" stop="20230214120000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Fresh with Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">1026 : Charades Night</sub-title><desc lang="en">Anna&apos;s preparing for a night of fun, food and friends as she hosts a Games Night. Using local ingredients, she&apos;s making plenty of snack foods like Quesadillas (bacon), Vegetable Chowder, Confetti Cornbread and Caramel Peanut Popcorn to keep her guests well fed and entertained.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/fresh-with-anna-olson/show-banner-fresh-with-anna-olson-5952d27e2609d-4e5dfe7d7f510f23801c915a977e2936b49a0cb7.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214120000 +0000" stop="20230214123000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Fresh with Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">1001 : Cooking For A Crowd</sub-title><desc lang="en">Cooking for a crowd can be a fun and gratifying task, it just takes a little planning, choosing your menu, and organizing tasks ahead of time. Watch as Anna takes us through the essentials of throwing a great dinner party. For her guests, Anna prepares a Mediterranean Potato Salad, juicy BBQ Back Ribs, and tops tender greens and grilled apricots with her Marinated Flank Steak. The table is set, the company is great and the food is delicious.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/fresh-with-anna-olson/show-banner-fresh-with-anna-olson-5952cddfa692a-f2bd4b0a06c0edb76c34a0ca399fda38786cc3a3.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214123000 +0000" stop="20230214130000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Fresh with Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">1002 : Fireman Hot &amp; Cold</sub-title><desc lang="en">In this episode Anna cooks for a team of firefighters with appetites only she can put out! She comes to the rescue with healthy, delicious meals that can be served up either hot or cold: a Sweet Potato Soup that&apos;s perfect for any season, Peach Oatmeal Griddle Cookies that are great for on the go, and a Salmon Chickpea Toss that&apos;s left-over friendly. A busy lifestyle doesn&apos;t mean you have to sacrifice on taste!</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/fresh-with-anna-olson/show-banner-fresh-with-anna-olson-5952cc15332b2-98fdd66be886c33440973aeaa8221940cbc2cb5d.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214130000 +0000" stop="20230214133000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Fresh with Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">1003 : Country Wedding</sub-title><desc lang="en">Anna&apos;s good friend Jennifer is getting married and Anna&apos;s gift is a wedding cake: a fabulous 4 tier White Chocolate Wedding Cake filled with local fresh berries and toped with green fondant. Anna also makes time to deliver three hors d&apos;oeuvres to the bridle party before the event: Artichoke Asiago Squares, Devilled Eggs, and Champagne Shrimp on Endive.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/fresh-with-anna-olson/show-banner-fresh-with-anna-olson-5952d27e2609d-4e5dfe7d7f510f23801c915a977e2936b49a0cb7.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214133000 +0000" stop="20230214140000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">Fresh with Anna Olson</title><sub-title lang="en">1004 : Beach Party</sub-title><desc lang="en">It&apos;s beautiful outside, so why not join Anna and her friends for an impromptu beach party. Anna prepares Roasted Pepper and Eggplant Salad and Three-Bean Salad before heading over to Minors Fisheries to pick up fresh local fish for her piÃ¨ce de rÃ©sistance: Lakeside Paella. Her friends enjoy helping her cook on the beach- roasting their Potato Prosciutto Kebabs in an open fire and stirring the slow cooking Lakeside Paella to perfection right on the beach.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/fresh-with-anna-olson/show-banner-fresh-with-anna-olson-5952cddfa692a-f2bd4b0a06c0edb76c34a0ca399fda38786cc3a3.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-G</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214140000 +0000" stop="20230214150000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">506 : Man In The Mirror</sub-title><desc lang="en">After a psychiatrist is murdered, Toby struggles to deal with a suspect with multiple personalities.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-5daf7932e5249-8d20d19d5b23f36aa93ab5a704c254f533b82b3f.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+LV</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214150000 +0000" stop="20230214160000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">507 : White Whale</sub-title><desc lang="en">The IIB team investigates a mayoral candidate for murder after Becker becomes zealously interested in Toby&apos;s gift.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-5daf7932e5249-8d20d19d5b23f36aa93ab5a704c254f533b82b3f.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+LV</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214160000 +0000" stop="20230214170000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">508 : The Fugitive</sub-title><desc lang="en">When Oz&apos;s neighbour is murdered, the IIB team discovers he was behind a legendary coin heist and must find the treasure to catch the killer.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-595554c886218-5628ea749f74679b95ab1f76da0dcad757f5641c.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+LV</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214170000 +0000" stop="20230214180000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">509 : Amuse Bouche</sub-title><desc lang="en">Toby and the team investigate the poisoning of a cooking show contestant on live TV.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-595554c886218-5628ea749f74679b95ab1f76da0dcad757f5641c.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+L</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214180000 +0000" stop="20230214190000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">510 : Family Secrets</sub-title><desc lang="en">Toby and the IIB team investigate evidence of sibling rivalry in the murder of a billionaire playboy.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-595554f09d62b-bea558184e2ddf3aaf8d54efead8722a8c3f5f56.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214190000 +0000" stop="20230214200000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">511 : Zero Recall</sub-title><desc lang="en">Toby is implicated in an armed kidnapping after being drugged and losing his memory.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-595554f09d62b-bea558184e2ddf3aaf8d54efead8722a8c3f5f56.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214200000 +0000" stop="20230214210000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">512 : An Innocent Man</sub-title><desc lang="en">Convinced an innocent man is taking the fall for a murder, Toby goes undercover as a prison inmate.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-5955552401a15-c85a3c78d1754fbe8eb372409aff33af8101fef3.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+LV</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214210000 +0000" stop="20230214220000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">513 : In Our Midst</sub-title><desc lang="en">Toby, Michelle and Dev investigate Becker&apos;s involvement in a criminal conspiracy.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-5955552401a15-c85a3c78d1754fbe8eb372409aff33af8101fef3.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+LV</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214220000 +0000" stop="20230214230000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">101 : I&apos;m An Adult Now</sub-title><desc lang="en">After rescuing a young woman in a car accident, Toby (Craig Olejnik) uses his telepathic ability to solve the kidnapping of a young boy.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-595554c886218-5628ea749f74679b95ab1f76da0dcad757f5641c.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14+V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230214230000 +0000" stop="20230215000000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">LEVERAGE</title><sub-title lang="en">401 : The Long Way Down Job</sub-title><desc lang="en">To take down a corrupt financier, the LEVERAGE team must recover lost evidence high up on a mountain, racing hired guns and killer weather.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/leverage/show-banner-leverage-61d4b9d652e60-c991021454e63d2fec08dce056d8ffbed27f4d56.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215000000 +0000" stop="20230215010000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">LEVERAGE</title><sub-title lang="en">402 : The 10 Li&apos;l Grifters Job</sub-title><desc lang="en">When the mark is killed suddenly in the middle of a sting, the team must scramble to complete the con and find the killer - before Nate goes down for murder.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/leverage/show-banner-leverage-61d4b9d652e60-c991021454e63d2fec08dce056d8ffbed27f4d56.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215010000 +0000" stop="20230215020000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">LEVERAGE</title><sub-title lang="en">403 : The 15 Minutes Job</sub-title><desc lang="en">To take down a corrupt PR consultant, the LEVERAGE team must build him up as a hero, then use his own methods against him.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/leverage/show-banner-leverage-61d4b9d7cacef-c7a642fe9a821d66acabe295ec99e643e65d4620.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215020000 +0000" stop="20230215030000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">LEVERAGE</title><sub-title lang="en">404 : The Van Gogh Job</sub-title><desc lang="en">On the trail of a lost Van Gogh, the team learns the painting was the center of a World War II love story between a black soldier and the white heiress he was forced to leave behind.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/leverage/show-banner-leverage-61d4b9d652e60-c991021454e63d2fec08dce056d8ffbed27f4d56.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215030000 +0000" stop="20230215040000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">LEVERAGE</title><sub-title lang="en">405 : The Hot Potato Job</sub-title><desc lang="en">The LEVERAGE team infiltrates the corrupt world of corporate agriculture to recover a stolen object worth millions: a one-of-a-kind potato.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/leverage/show-banner-leverage-61d4b9d799730-4af0cba6b3fb3cb443afef6ad91841084abefd94.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215040000 +0000" stop="20230215050000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">LEVERAGE</title><sub-title lang="en">406 : The Carnival Job</sub-title><desc lang="en">The LEVERAGE team infiltrates a high-tech home to steal a revolutionary computer chip, only to have the family&apos;s child abducted from a carnival during the heist.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/leverage/show-banner-leverage-61d4b9d7cacef-c7a642fe9a821d66acabe295ec99e643e65d4620.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG L,V</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215050000 +0000" stop="20230215060000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">The Listener</title><sub-title lang="en">102 : Emotional Rescue</sub-title><desc lang="en">After saving a childhood friend from a burning building, Toby (Craig Olejnik) tracks town an arsonist that he believes might be responsible for a series of fires in the city.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/the-listener/show-banner-the-listener-595554f09d62b-bea558184e2ddf3aaf8d54efead8722a8c3f5f56.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-14</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215060000 +0000" stop="20230215063000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">120 : The Atta&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">Steve won $75,000 in the lottery and he&apos;s buying his mom, Mona, a house. Annette, his very pregnant wife, is not happy with the decision. With the two women in his life at odds, Steve is forced to play both sides.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215063000 +0000" stop="20230215070000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">121 : The Marchenko&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">Natalia desperately wants to claim her independence and buy a downtown condo. Her parents insist that she stay in the suburbs. With her tenacious best friend by her side, Natalia goes head-to-head with her parents to get what she wants.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215070000 +0000" stop="20230215073000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">122 : The Mian&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">Omer needs to move out of his parent&apos;s house but his parents want him to live with them forever! He bands together with his sister, Sarah, to wear them down so he can fly the coop and buy a downtown condo.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215073000 +0000" stop="20230215080000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">123 : The Wendt&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">Back from the Navy, Kevin plans to buy a modern turnkey home with his girlfriend, Ainsley. But Mom and Dad will only consider fixer-uppers and a place close to theirs. The search begins and the real estate power struggle has Kevin swearing like a sailor in no time.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215080000 +0000" stop="20230215083000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">124 : The Suppiah&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">Sindhu is desperate to move out the family home and buy a downtown condo. Her parents want her to get married and find a place close to home. Sindhu is forced to put her foot down or her dreams of independence will vanish before her very eyes.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215083000 +0000" stop="20230215090000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">125 : The Davis&apos;s</sub-title><desc lang="en">Privileged but penniless theatre students Katie and Howard need to ditch their dingy one-bedroom apartment and buy their first home. Their renovation expert parents Insist that the kids take in tenants and roommates. Katie and Howard love to act but Playing the part of the landlord is too much drama for them to handle.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215090000 +0000" stop="20230215093000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">126 : The Lynches</sub-title><desc lang="en">Single-mother Toni, 41, is fiercely independent but runs straight to &quot;Mommy Moneybags&quot; when she decides to buy a bigger house. Mom agrees to bankroll the move, but that doesn&apos;t mean she&apos;s going to write a blank cheque or keep her opinions to herself. But that doesn&apos;t stop Toni from pushing back on her mouthy mother, and the two set out on a house hunt that might be doomed from the start.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
<programme start="20230215093000 +0000" stop="20230215100000 +0000" channel="IONPlusEast.us"><title lang="en">My House, Your Money</title><sub-title lang="en">201 : The Beers</sub-title><desc lang="en">Single mother Towa can&apos;t handle the tiny house she shares with her four-year-old daughter Sienna and her mother, Rene, so it&apos;s time to buy something better. But it&apos;s Irene who holds the purse strings and she demands a house while Towa desperately wants a swish condo. And Towa&apos;s mother insists on using a realtor that she has fired in the past. The battle lines are drawn and real estate rumble begins.</desc><icon src="https://ionplustv.com/static/programs/shows/my-house-your-money/show-banner-my-house-your-money-5c2d04fad719c-7ad524fcf1f1cb07c799a85a1ae8834cb4f480db.png"/><rating system="MPA"><value>TV-PG</value></rating></programme>
</tv>